<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Home</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.134.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 13:18:10 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Build Career Fintech</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-build-career-fintech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 13:18:10 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-build-career-fintech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been giving some thoughts to why domain knowledge is important in building a career in fintech. I thought I could share some of my thoughts on the topic. I have put in QnA format to make it easier to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-focus-on-building-domain-expertise-in-fintech&#34;&gt;Why focus on building domain expertise in fintech?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the advancements we&amp;rsquo;re seeing in artificial intelligence and development tools, the ability to translate well-defined requirements into code is no longer the primary differentiator it once was. Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang takes it further and says&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Event Driven Architecture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-event-driven-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 16:19:07 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/why-event-driven-architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of event-driven architecture. I think it&amp;rsquo;s a great way to build scalable and resilient systems. I thought I would share some of my thoughts in this QnA format&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-use-event-driven-design&#34;&gt;Why use event-driven design?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Event-driven design should be considered for many system designs due to its ability to address common challenges in modern software architecture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scalability: Events can be queued and processed asynchronously, allowing for better handling of high loads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Availability: Systems can continue to accept events even if downstream processors are temporarily unavailable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evolvability: The decoupled nature of event-driven systems makes it easier to modify or replace individual components.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resilience: Queuing mechanisms provide a buffer against failures and allow for easier recovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it&amp;rsquo;s important to weigh these benefits against potential drawbacks like increased complexity and the learning curve for developers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Resilience Journey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-resilince-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 13:56:31 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-resilince-journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What does having a growth mindset mean to me? Let me share an experience from my younger days that shaped my understanding of resilience and personal growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-challenge-society-of-actuaries-exam&#34;&gt;The Challenge: Society of Actuaries Exam&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was preparing for my Society of Actuaries P1 exam. The preparation materials were expensive - these books cost north of a hundred dollars at that time. I had gone through the book thoroughly and felt I had a solid conceptual understanding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 13:51:34 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; text, and this is &lt;em&gt;emphasized&lt;/em&gt; text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; website!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extra pressure
git branch -M main&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
